Mss.Ms.Coll.56
American Philosophical Society
Bagnold was the first recipient of the G.K. Warren Prize of the (U.S.) National Academy of Sciences in 1969. In 1970, he received the Penrose Medal from the Geological Society of America. He was a Fellow of the Imperial College, University of London, and in 1971 received the Wollaston Medal, Geological Society of London. In 1974 he was elected a Foreign Honorary Member of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. The International Association of Sedimentologists presented him the Sorby Medal in 1978; and he was given the David Linton Award by the British Geomorphological Research Group in 1981. He was awarded honorary D.Sc. degrees from the University of East Anglia and from the Danish University of Aarhus. His memoirs were published in "Sand, Wind and War" (University of Arizona Press, 1991). Other papers and correspondence of R.A. Bagnold are in the Churchill Archives Centre, Cambridge (U.K.), there comprising 12 boxes and a plan chest. [N.B.: Leopold's outgoing correspondence to Bagnold was written in longhand with no copies retained; Bagnold had not kept the correspondence he received from Leopold (fide Luna B. Leopold to "Kevin" [Thomas Kevin Cherry, Mellon Library Intern, APS], 1991, correspondence in APS Manuscripts Dept. Legal File for Leopold).]
The Bagnold family, including his wife, Penelope, formed a close relationship with the Leopold family, which is also represented in the general correspondence in this collection.
LUNA B. LEOPOLD was elected to APS membership in 1972. Among numerous other awards and honors he was the recipient of the Kirk Bryan Award of the Geological Society of America (1958); Distinguished Service Medal, U.S. Department of the Interior (1958); Veth Medal, Royal Netherlands Geographical Society (1963); medalist of the University of Liege, Belgium (1966); Cullum Medal, American Geographical Society (1968); Member, (U.S.) National Academy of Sciences (1968); Distinguished Service Citation, University of Wisconsin (1969); Fellow, American Academy of Arts and Sciences (1969); Rockefeller Public Service Award (1972); Warren Prize, National Academy of Sciences (1973); "Rivers 1976" award, American Society of Civil Engineers; Fellow, California Academy of Sciences (1982); Forchheimer Foundation Senior Fellow, Hebrew University, Jerusalem (1983); Busk Medal, Royal Geographical Society (1983); Berkeley Citation, University of California (1986); David Linton Award, British Geomorphological Research Group (1986); Linsley Award, American Institute of Hydrology (1988, 1990); Henry P. Caulfield, Jr., Medal, American Water Resources Association (1991); Distinguished Career Award, Quaternary Geology and Geomorphology Division, Geological Society of America (1991); (U.S.) National Medal of Science (1991); Palladium Medal, National Audubon Socity and American Association of Engineering Societies (1991); Robert E. Horton Medal, American Geophysical Union (1993); Penrose Medal, Geological Society of America (1994); Ian Campbell Medal, American Geological Institute (2000); and, posthumously (only by his death a few months before the award ceremonies), the Benjamin Franklin Medal in Earth and Environmental Science from The Franklin Institute in Philadelphia, 2006, which was accepted by his brother, Carl.
He also received honorary degrees from several schools: D.Geogr., University of Ottawa (1970); and D.Sc. degrees from Iowa Wesleyan University (1972), University of Wisconsin at Madison (1980), St. Andrews University, Scotland (1981), and University of Murcia, Spain (1988).
Luna Leopold was born 8 October 1915 in Albuquerque, New Mexico. Through his mother, Estella Bergère, he was descended from the Luna family, one of the pioneer Spanish families of New Mexico.
Leopold was first married to Caroline, with whom he had two children. The marriage ended in divorce. He married in 1973 Barbara Baker Beck, widow of Leverett Nelson. Leopold's professional and private lives were always inseparable, but even more pronounced during his working-retirement years. This is revealed by the content of his correspondence, of course, but most notably testified to by the fact that many of the salutations, even those that are professional in nature, are addressed to both "Luna and Barbara". The Leopolds opened their home in Berkeley, California, and their summer cabin in Pinedale, Wyoming, to a constant flow of guests; some were hunting and fishing friends, while many others were traveling and vacationing professionals engaged with Leopold in his avocational studies of streams near his "backyards" or who paid courtesy calls on the Leopolds. Even correspondence between members of the Leopold family (his siblings and his children) meanders from personal commentaries to discussions of various family not-for-profit foundations, professional affiliations, and business affairs.
He died 23 February 2006 in Berkeley, California. Five days earlier, he had written in his notebook, "I want to start a new book but the energy is lacking... ." His last notations also record that he had also been hard at work finalizing preparations for the "Leopold Conference" commemorating the environmental philosophies of his father, Aldo. His long-time colleague, coauthor and friend, Claudio Vita-Finzi of The Natural History Museum, London, was his memorialist for the Geological Society of America and the American Philosophical Society. An obituary appeared in newspapers across the country, including "The New York Times" and "The Washington Post". He was survived by his first wife, Carolyn Michaels; his children, Bruce and Madelyn, and step-children T. Leverett "Rett" Nelson and Carolyn T. "Carrie" Nelson; and three siblings, Nina Leopold Bradley, A. Carl Leopold, and Estella B. Leopold (APS 2000). His brother, A. Starker Leopold, and his second wife, Barbara, predeceased him in 1983 and 2004, respectively.
Geology.; Geomorphology--Fluvial; Hydrology.; River sediments.; Sediment transport.; Sedimentology.
- I. Correspondence, Bulk, 1986-2006; 1967-2006; 5.0 Linear feet 13 boxes; Leopold, Luna B. (Luna Bergère), 1915-2006
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I contains Leopold's inbound correspondence mostly during his retirement years, 1986-2006, although earlier years are modestly represented. This is mixed professional and personal correspondence from individuals; professional and personal correspondence with commercial or professional firms; and some correspondence with professional organizations, societies, and publishers. A few copies of Leopold's outbound correspondence are present in places, but as a rule there is very little outbound correspondence in this collection.
  Correspondence will also be found throughout other Series in the Luna B. Leopold Papers. Leopold retained pertinent items of correspondence associated with reference and personal files, even within his manuscripts and bound collection of publications. Scope and Content notes for pertinent individual folders in this finding aid will indicate which among them include correspondence, and from whom.
  Most correspondence was originally grouped in folders arranged chronologically by year, with some additional, separate folders for specific organizations or agencies. The chronological component has been arranged alphabetically for this collection. The fact that Leopold filed all of his professional and personal correspondence together tells of professional and private lives that he treated inseparably; and that he kept all, or a great deal, of it tells something of his feelings toward everyone with whom he came in touch, not to mention a consumate need to document his activities. This is revealed by the content of the correspondence, of course, but most notably testified to by the fact that many of the salutations (even those in correspondence that is professional in nature) are addressed to both "Luna and Barbara". The Leopolds opened their home in Berkeley, California, and their summer cabin in Pinedale, Wyoming, to a constant flow of guests; some were hunting and fishing friends, while many others were traveling and vacationing professionals engaged with Leopold in his avocational studies of streams near his "backyards" or who paid courtesy calls on the Leopolds.
  Even correspondence between members of the Leopold family (his siblings and his children) meanders from personal commentary to attention to various family not-for-profit foundations, professional affiliations, and business affairs; sometimes in the same letter. These reasons, as well as Leopold's own preferences in filing correspondence, preclude a segregation of the personal and professional correspondence.
  Quite a lot of correspondence was also found (even some of the professional correspondence) signed by its senders only by given names; another measure of the breadth of the Leopolds' circle of friends, acquaintances, and coworkers. Many of these items were not accompanied by other means of identification; for example, a full name and return address; and in fact, many items of correspondence are on photographic postcards from far-flung locales, usually overseas. Those correspondents whose surnames were known or otherwise determined through other evidence have been foldered in Subseries 1; Leopold in many cases kept the mailing envelopes, which provided these clues that otherwise would have been absent. Those correspondents who have not been determined beyond their signed given names are foldered in Subseries 2, along with correspondence whose signers have not been deciphered and unsigned correspondence.
  In some cases of institutional and organizational correspondence, the items are filed under the institutional/organizational name rather than the individual from whom the correspondence was received. In these cases Leopold had been performing some activity for the institution/organization or was being informed of or inquired about some matter by them; the correspondent was the agent communicating on behalf of the institution or organization.
  - 1. Correspondence Identified by Full Names, 1967-2006; 4.5 ln. ft. 11 boxes
    Subseries 1 contains professional and personal correspondence received from individuals and others whose names are fully identified. In some cases, the correspondence is signed only with given names, but other evidence was available to identify the full name of the correspondent.
    - Abbey, Edward, 1985; Abbey, Edward, 1927-1989 (Box 1)
    - Adams, Jean, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Aircraft Owners and Pilots Association, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Alberts, Bruce, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Aldo Leopold Elementary School (Madison, Wisconsin), 1987 (Box 1)
    - Aldo Leopold Shack Foundation, 1982-1994 (Box 1)
    - Aldo Leopold Society (Institute of Ecosystem Studies), 1994 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Clarence R., 2000 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Henry M., 1991 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Julia C., undated (Box 1)
    - Allen, Robert, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Alter, Harvey, 1985 (Box 1)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1993 (Box 1)
    - American Geographical Society, 1988 (Box 1)
    - American Geological Institute, 2000 (Box 1)
    - American Geophysical Union, 1978-2000 (Box 1)
    - American Institute of Hydrology, 1987-1993 (Box 1)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1978-2006; undated (Box 1)
    - "American Scientist", 1978 (Box 1)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
    - American Water Resources Association, 1990-1998 (Box 1)
    - American Wilderness Alliance, 1981-1986 (Box 1)
    - Amundson, Ronald, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Andrews, Edmund D., 1986 (Box 1)
    - "Annual Review of Earth and Planetary Sciences", 1997, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Applied Ecological Services, 1989, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Aráuz, Rodolfo, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - Archives of Contemporary Scientists, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Asherwood Environmental Science Center, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Association of Engineering Geologists, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Association of Retired Soil Conservation Employees, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Atkin, Barbara, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Australian Water Resources Council, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Averett, Robert C., 1983-1990 (Box 1)
    - Averitt, Neil, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Babbitt, Bruce, 2000; Babbitt, Bruce E., 1938- (Box 1)
    - Babulski, Katrina, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Badash, Roger, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Bagnold, Dorothy Plank, undated (Box 1)
    - Bagnold, Stephen, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Baier, Carol, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Baker, Linda F., 2003 (Box 1)
    - Baker, Victor R., 1980 (Box 1)
    - Balch, Philip G., 2000 (Box 1)
    - Baldwin, Kenneth, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Bally London Shoe Co. Ltd., 1986 (Box 1)
    - Bancroft School, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Barber, Teri Jo, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Barker, Margaret L., 1986; undated (Box 1)
    - Barnes, Kathryn, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Barnett, Franklyn M., 1986 (Box 1)
    - Barth, Gilbert, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Bathurst, James C., 1978 (Box 1)
    - Batisse, Claude, 1978-2004 (Box 1)
    - Batisse, Laurence, undated (Box 1)
    - Bay Institute (The), 1988 (Box 1)
    - Beard, Daniel D., 1999 (Box 1)
    - Beck, Frances, undated (Box 1)
    - Bedini, Silvio A., 2001 (Box 1)
    - Beer, Charles G., 1983 (Box 1)
    - Behr, Peter H., 1983 (Box 1)
    - Behrman, Robert A., 1994 (Box 1)
    - Bell, Kevin, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Belt, Charles B., Jr., 1978-1994 (Box 1)
    - Bender, Richard, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Bengeyfield, Peter, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Berger, Antony R., 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Berger, Michael, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Berkeley-Albany Municipal Court (California), 1982 (Box 1)
    - Berkeley Committee to Keep Jets Over the Bay, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Berkeley Garden Club, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Berkeley Repertory Theatre, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Bern, Marshall, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Berry, Phillip S., 1989 (Box 1)
    - Berry & Berry, Law Offices, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Biblical Archaeology Society, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Bigler Cole, Heidi, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Binder, Randy, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Birt, Christine, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Bjock, Jack, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Blanpied, Karen and Eric, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Black, Martha, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Blackwell Scientific Publications, Inc., 1986 (Box 1)
    - Bluck, Brian J., 1980 (Box 1)
    - Boal, Gillian, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Bogost, Meyer S., 1988 (Box 2)
    - Bohlen, Steve, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Bookey, Natalie, undated (Box 2)
    - Boudreau, E. H., 1992 (Box 2)
    - Bourland, Tom, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Bradley, Charles, 1988, 1993 (Box 2)
      Includes pressed leaf.
    - Bradley, David and Lil, undated
    - Bradley, Nina Leopold, 1980-2006; undated (Box 2)
      Includes photos.
    - Bradley, William C., 1999 (Box 2)
    - Brady, Valerie, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Brandywine Conservancy, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Bredehoeft, John D., 1988 (Box 2)
    - Briggs, Robert O., 1989-2000 (Box 2)
    - British Geomorphological Research Group, 1986 (Box 2)
    - British-German Symposium in Geomorpology, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Brower, Barbara, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Mary Lou, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Perry J., 1998 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Polly L., 1985 (Box 2)
    - Brownlie, William R., 1980 (Box 2)
    - Bryan, Rorke, 1987; undated (Box 2)
    - Bull, William B., 1988-1994; undated (Box 2)
    - Bunte, Kristin, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Burbank, Jay, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Burke Museum of Natural History and Culture, undated (Box 2)
    - Burt, James E., 2002 (Box 2)
    - Burzlander, Doris, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Butler, Paul, 1985, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
    - Bagnold, Stephen, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Buttimer, Anne, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Buzea, Dan C., 1978 (Box 2)
    - California. Department of Forestry, 1982-1987 (Box 2)
    - California. Governor-Elect, Office of, 1998 (Box 2)
    - California. Governor's Office of Emergency Services, 1998 (Box 2)
    - California Academy of Sciences, 1996 (Box 2)
    - California First Bank, 1986 (Box 2)
    - California Institute of Technology, 1986 (Box 2)
    - California Tahoe Conservancy, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Callicott, J. Baird, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Campbell, Charles R., undated (Box 2)
    - Campbell, Chris, undated (Box 2)
    - Campbell, Christy, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Campbell, Karin, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Campbell, Kathleen, 1994; undated (Box 2)
    - Camrud, Jo, 2000 (Box 2)
    - "Canadian Journal of Fisheries and Aquatic Sciences", 1981 (Box 2)
    - Carney, John Otis, 1984 (Box 2)
    - "Catena", 1993 (Box 2)
    - Catron, Tom, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Christensen, Martha, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Church, Michael, 1993, 2005; undated (Box 2)
    - Churchill, Jason, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Citizen Ambassador Program, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Clarke, Grayson and Frank, 1983, 1986, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
    - Climatology Research Group, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Cloern, James E., 1999 (Box 2)
    - Coalition to Restore Urban Waters, Southwest Region, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Coates, Donald R., 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - Coe, Robert, 1978 (Box 2)
    - "CoEvolution Quarterly", 1978 (Box 2)
    - Cohen, Philip, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Cole, Charles W., undated (Box 2)
    - Cole, Geoff, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Collins, Brian, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Collins, Dolores (Mrs. John L. Collins), 1979, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Collins, Genna, undated (Box 2)
    - Collins, Joshua N., 1993 (Box 2)
    - Collins, William Wirt, Jr. (Mr. and Mrs.), 1980 (Box 2)
    - Colophon Hand Bookbindery, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Columbia University Press, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Conaway, James, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Conkey, Meg, undated (Box 3)
    - Conn, Kathe, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Corbett, H. Roger, Jr., 1988, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Cosmos Club, 1985, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Costa, John E., 1986 (Box 3)
    - Council on Environmental Quality (Executive Office of the President [United States]), 1980 (Box 3)
    - Cragwall, Joseph S., 1988 (Box 3)
    - Crausaz, Winston, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Crosby, Alexander L., 1967, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Crowell, John C., 1997 (Box 3)
    - Curry, Jean Warren, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Dahlke, John, 1998-2005 (Box 3)
    - Darpino, Mark N., 1999 (Box 3)
    - David, Liz, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Dawdy, David R., 1980-2005 (Box 3)
    - Delk, Robert, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Dello Russo, Regina E., 1998 (Box 3)
    - Dellums, Ronald V., 1993 (Box 3)
    - DePaolo, Don, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Dietrich, William E., 1986 (Box 3)
    - Doll, Barbara, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Douglas, Robert F., 2001-2002 (Box 3)
    - Dove, Louise E., 2002 (Box 3)
    - Dover Publications, Inc., 1994 (Box 3)
    - Doyle, Martin W., 2004 (Box 3)
    - Dream Garden Press, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Dubois, Mark, undated (Box 3)
    - Dudley, James C., 1984 (Box 3)
    - Dugere, David (Mrs.), 1990 (Box 3)
    - Duke University. Graduate School, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
    - Dunne, Bettylou (Sherry, Bettylou), 1980-2004; undated (Box 3)
    - Duane, Thomas, 1987, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Dury, George H., 1980 (Box 3)
    - Dushek, George, 1985 (Box 3)
    - "Earth Surface Processes", 1978 (Box 3)
    - Earthjustice, 2004 (Box 3)
    - East Bay Municipal Utility District (California), 1993, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Eaton, Gordon P., 1994 (Box 3)
    - Ecological Cities Project, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
    - Ecological Society of America, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Edgebrook Conference (University of California at Berkeley), 1980 (Box 3)
    - Edmondson, W. T., 1980 (Box 3)
    - Elder, William, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Elfring, Chris, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Elliott-Fisk, Deborah, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Elsevier Science Publishers, 1985 (Box 3)
    - El-Zur, Arieh, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Emmett, William W., 1978-2005 (Box 3)
    - "Encyclopedia of the Environment", 1992-1993 (Box 3)
    - Environmental Action Committee of West Marin (California), 1997 (Box 3)
    - Environmental Law and Policy Center of the Midwest, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Environmental Law Institute, 1992-1996 (Box 3)
    - Euphrat, Fred, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Faber, Phyllis M., 1986 (Box 3)
    - Fahnestock, Robert K., 1978 (Box 3)
    - Falconer, Kay, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Fandek, John, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Federation of Fly Fishers, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Feiss, Julian W., 1979 (Box 3)
    - Feldman, Mark, 2000, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Fiedler, Albert G., 1990 (Box 3)
    - First Wisconsin National Bank of Madison, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Fletcher, Colin, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Florsheim, Joan, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Foland, Sara S., 1999 (Box 4)
    - Foley & Lardner, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Forani-Wills, L., 1977 (Box 4)
    - Forbes, William, 1993, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Ford Foundation, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Foundation of Fine Coins, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Francis, Carolyn F., 1985 (Box 4)
    - Frank, Laurence, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Frankonia-Jagd, Hofmann and Co., undated (Box 4)
    - Freeman, Cooper and Co., 1989 (Box 4)
    - Freson, George, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Frexes, Patrica J., 1980 (Box 4)
    - Friends of Creeks in Urban Settings (F.O.C.U.S.), 1987 (Box 4)
    - Friends of the Earth, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Friends of the Napa River, 1998 (Box 4)
      Includes photo.
    - Frissell, Chris, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Frome, Michael, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Galbraith, Alan F., 1980, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Gallistel, Albert F., 1982-1997; undated (Box 4)
      Includes photos (35mm transparencies).
    - García-Ruiz, José M., 1988 (Box 4)
    - Garden Club of America, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Gardner, Tom (Gardner, Vernon T.), 1991-1993 (Box 4)
    - Garnett, William, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Gary, Walter J., 1996 (Box 4)
    - Gellis, Allen, 1998-1999 (Box 4)
    - Geological Society of America, 1978-2005 (Box 4)
    - George Allen & Unwin, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Gerson, Hadassah, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Ghibaudo, Guido, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Gibbons, Boyd, 1979, 1992; undated (Box 4)
    - Gibbs M. Smith, Inc., 1986-1987 (Box 4)
    - Gill, Harriet, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Gillam, Mary, undated (Box 4)
    - Girdharry, Lila M. (Leverson), undated (Box 4)
    - Goldman, Steve, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Goodwin, Peter, 1983, 1989, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Golden Gate Audubon Society, undated (Box 4)
    - Goolsby, Ann, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Goren-Inbar, Naama, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Gracie, James W., 1989-1990 (Box 4)
    - Graf, William L., 1994 (Box 4)
    - Graves, John, 1981 (Box 4)
    - "Gray's Sporting Journal", 1979 (Box 4)
    - Greater Yellowstone Coalition, 1986-1990 (Box 4)
    - Green River Valley Land Trust, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Greenman, David W., 1987 (Box 4)
    - Griebenow, Kevin, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Grissinger, Earl H., 1980 (Box 4)
    - Groat, Charles G., 2003 (Box 4)
    - Grossinger, Robin, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Groundwater Resources Association, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Gupta, Avijit, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Gustafson, Chris, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Hack, John T., circa 1983 (Box 4)
    - Hadley, Richard F., 1998 (Box 4)
    - Haible, Will, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Half Moon Bar Lodge, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Hall, Francis R., 1984 (Box 4)
    - Hall, Stephen A., 1988 (Box 4)
    - Halprin, David, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Halton, Connie, undated (Box 4)
    - Hanna, Frances (Mrs. Warren Hanna), 1988 (Box 4)
    - Harberg, Mark C., 1999 (Box 4)
    - Harrelson, Cheryl, 1993, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Hart, John, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Hart, M., 2000 (Box 4)
    - Hartman, Elizabeth, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Harvard University Press, 1994 (Box 4)
    - Harvey, Adrian, 1994; undated (Box 4)
    - Harvey, Mark, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Harwood, M. M., 1980 (Box 4)
    - Haynes, Vance, 1996-1997, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Heckman, Mark, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Hedgpeth, Joel W., 1989 (Box 4)
    - Hegemann, Ingeborg E., 1980 (Box 4)
    - Heinz, Dion L., 1987 (Box 4)
    - Henningson, Durham and Richardson, Sciences Division, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Hereford, Richard, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Hey, R. D., 1980 (Box 4)
    - Hickenbottom, Jennifer A. S., undated (Box 4)
    - "High Country News", 1987, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Hill, Elizabeth, 1994 (Box 4)
      Includes correspondence from Dawdy, David R.
    - Hirsch, Mary, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Hitchcock, Bert, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
    - Holt, John W., 1993 (Box 5)
    - Holz, Bernard, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Hotchkiss, William R., 1993 (Box 5)
    - Houck, John, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Howard, Alan D., undated (Box 5)